( birds chirping )
( Kirito groaning )
WHAT THE HELL?
WHERE AM I?
I REMEMBER BEING
AT AGIL’S PLACE.
THEN I LEFT WITH ASUNA.
BUT I CAN’T REMEMBER
WHAT HAPPENED NEXT.
( gasps )
HUH?
MY CLOTHES.
AM I IN A GAME RIGHT NOW?
COMMAND.
LOG OUT?
HUH?
WAY TOO REALISTIC
TO BE A 3-D OBJECT,
SO THIS AIN’T A GAME.
AM I DREAMING? WAIT.
THAT’S IT.
THIS IS THE UNDERWORLD.
I’M HOOKED UP TO THE S.T.L.
BUT THAT CAN’T BE RIGHT.
IF I’M DIVING IN THE S.T.L.,
MY MEMORIES OF THE REAL WORLD
SHOULD BE BLOCKED,
AND I CAN STILL REMEMBER
HANGING OUT
WITH ASUNA AND SINON.
KIKUOKA! HIGA?
ANYONE! ABORT THE DIVE!
I THINK THERE’S
SOMETHING WRONG IN HERE!
( sighs )
( gulping )
THIS IS TOO REAL FOR V.R.
- ( ax chops )
- ( water splashes )
( ax chops )
♪
( gasps )
WHAT WAS THAT?
I DON’T KNOW WHY,
BUT IT FELT SO NOSTALGIC
AND FRUSTRATING.
♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ WHOA, OH OH ♪
♪ WHOA OH, OH, OH OH OH ♪
♪ DO YOU BELIEVE YOURSELF? ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ SHINY SWORD, MY DIAMOND ♪
♪ IT’S TIME ♪
( singing in Japanese )
( birds chirping )
( ax rings )
( Kirito gasps )
♪
( gasps )
Eugeo: HMM?
( Kirito stammers )
Eugeo: WHO ARE YOU?
ARE YOU FROM AROUND HERE?
Kirito: IS HE A TESTER LIKE ME,
OR IS HE AN NPC?
Eugeo: DO YOU HAVE A NAME?
Kirito: UM...
YEAH, I GOT ONE.
IT’S KIRITO.
Eugeo: KIRITO?
Kirito: I CAME
FROM THE FOREST OVER THERE,
BUT I’M NOT SURE
WHERE I AM OR ANYTHING.
Eugeo: THE FOREST.
OH. YOU MEAN FROM THE SOUTH?
DID YOU WALK
ALL THE WAY FROM ZAKKARIA?
Kirito: NO, I DON’T THINK SO.
I MEAN, IT’S LIKE--
I DON’T KNOW HOW I GOT HERE.
I CAN’T REMEMBER.
Eugeo: WHAT?
THEN, WHERE DO YOU LIVE?
CAN YOU REMEMBER
THE NAME OF THE TOWN?
Kirito: UM, NO.
EVERYTHING’S A BLANK.
I WOKE UP,
AND I WAS IN THE FOREST.
Eugeo: I HEARD THE STORIES,
BUT I NEVER THOUGHT
I’D MEET A REAL, LIVE
LOST CHILD OF VECTA.
I CAN’T BELIEVE IT.
Kirito: HUH? WHAT’S A VECTA?
Eugeo: WAIT. ISN’T THAT
WHAT THEY’RE CALLED
WHERE YOU’RE FROM?
WHEN SOMEONE
DISAPPEARS FROM A VILLAGE,
THEN SUDDENLY TURNS UP
IN A FOREST OR A FIELD,
THAT’S WHAT THEY’RE CALLED,
A CHILD OF VECTA.
THE DARK GOD VECTA
LIKES TO PRANK HUMANS
BY SNATCHING THEM UP,
STEALING THEIR MEMORIES,
AND PLOPPING THEM DOWN
SOMEWHERE FAR FROM HOME.
Kirito: OHH.
I GUESS THAT MUST HAVE BEEN
WHAT HAPPENED TO ME, THEN.
HIS RESPONSES ARE
WAY TOO NATURAL FOR AN NPC.
I’LL TRY THE DIRECT APPROACH.
ANYWAY, I’M KIND OF STUCK, SO...
I WANNA LEAVE.
Eugeo: UH...
HMM.
YES, I’M SURE YOU DO.
I THINK I KNOW HOW TO HELP YOU.
THE FOREST IS HUGE AND
EASY TO GET LOST IN, THOUGH.
I CAN SHOW YOU A PATH
THAT LEADS NORTH.
- AS LONG AS YOU STICK TO IT...
- Kirito: UM, NO.
- Eugeo: YOU WON’T--
- Kirito: SORRY.
I WANNA LOG OUT NOW!
Eugeo: "LOG OUT"?
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
Kirito: DAMN IT.
IT’S SLANG, YOU KNOW?
IT’S LIKE A FASTER WAY
OF SAYING,
"I NEED TO FIND
A PLACE TO STAY."
Eugeo: REALLY?
I NEVER HEARD THAT ONE BEFORE.
( Kirito chuckles )
NOW WHAT?
HE COULD BE A TESTER,
BUT IF HE IS,
HIS MEMORIES
ARE DEFINITELY BLOCKED.
Eugeo:
MY VILLAGE IS CALLED RULID,
AND IT’S BEYOND THOSE TREES.
BUT WE DON’T GET MANY TRAVELERS,
SO THERE’S NO INN.
I THINK IF WE GO TO THE CHURCH
AND EXPLAIN YOUR SITUATION
TO SISTER AZALIA,
SHE MIGHT AGREE TO PUT YOU UP.
Kirito: OH. OKAY, THEN.
I’LL GO TO YOUR VILLAGE
AND TALK TO HER.
Eugeo: WAIT A MOMENT!
Kirito: HUH?
Eugeo: YOU’RE A STRANGER
IN THESE PARTS.
I DON’T THINK
THE GUARDS AT THE GATE
ARE GOING TO LET YOU IN
SO EASILY.
HUH. YOU KNOW WHAT?
IF I GO WITH YOU AND TALK
TO THEM, THEY SHOULD UNDERSTAND.
Kirito: THAT’D BE GREAT
IF YOU DID.
THANKS A LOT.
Eugeo: HMM.
BUT I CAN’T GO YET.
I HAVE TO FINISH MY WORK FIRST,
AND I WON’T BE DONE
FOR ANOTHER FOUR HOURS.
Kirito: I DON’T MIND.
I CAN WAIT.
THAT IS, AS LONG
AS IT’S OKAY WITH YOU.
Eugeo: OF COURSE!
HAVE A SEAT ANYWHERE YOU LIKE,
AND I’LL GET TO WORK.
OH. I HAVEN’T TOLD YOU
MY NAME, HAVE I?
Kirito: N-NO.
♪
Eugeo: MY NAME IS EUGEO.
HOW DO YOU DO?
Kirito: EUGEO?
SOUNDS FAMILIAR.
Eugeo: WHAT’S WRONG, SIR KIRITO?
Kirito: UH...
( sighs )
NOTHING.
OH, AND YOU CAN
JUST CALL ME KIRITO.
Eugeo: OKAY. NICE TO MAKE
YOUR ACQUAINTANCE, KIRITO.
- THAT’S RIGHT!
- Kirito: HUH?
Eugeo: YOU MUST BE HUNGRY.
Kirito: OH, THANKS A LOT.
HE’S DEFINITELY NOT AN NPC.
STILL NOT SURE IF HE’S
A TEST PLAYER, THOUGH.
OR MAYBE THIS ISN’T V.R.
MAYBE THIS IS REAL.
Eugeo: THE ONLY GOOD THING
ABOUT THIS BREAD
IS IT KEEPS FOR A LONG TIME,
BUT JUST TO BE SAFE...
( Kirito gasps )
OKAY. LET ME TRY THAT.
( gasps )
THAT SETTLES IT.
THIS AIN’T REALITY
OR A PARALLEL DIMENSION.
IT’S V.R.
- Eugeo: HEY, KIRITO.
- Kirito: WHAT?
Eugeo: DID YOU FORGET HOW TO USE
THE STACIA WINDOW, TOO?
Kirito: NO, ’COURSE NOT.
Eugeo: YOU CAN TAKE YOUR TIME
EATING IT IF YOU WANT.
IT STILL HAS
PLENTY OF LIFE LEFT.
IF THIS WERE SUMMER,
YOU CAN BET IT WOULDN’T
KEEP NEARLY AS LONG.
Kirito: MM.
( groans )
HOLY...
Eugeo: IT’S NOT VERY GOOD, HUH?
I GET THEM FROM THE BAKERY
EVERY MORNING ON MY WAY HERE,
BUT IT’S SO EARLY,
THEY ONLY HAVE DAY-OLD BREAD.
AND I DON’T HAVE TIME TO GO BACK
AT NOON FOR FRESH ONES.
Kirito: THAT SUCKS.
DO YOU HAVE TIME TO MAKE LUNCH
OR HAVE SOMEONE ELSE MAKE IT?
( Eugeo gasps )
WELL, ACTUALLY,
SOMEONE USED TO BRING ME
MY LUNCH EVERY DAY,
BUT THAT WAS YEARS AGO.
OH, WELL.
Kirito: SO WHY’D THEY STOP?
♪
Eugeo: SHE WAS
MY CHILDHOOD FRIEND.
SHE WAS THE SAME AGE AS ME.
WHEN WE WERE LITTLE,
WE PLAYED TOGETHER ALL THE TIME.
AND AFTER I RECEIVED MY CALLING,
SHE WOULD BRING ME LUNCH
EVERY DAY WITHOUT FAIL.
BUT THEN...
BECAUSE OF ME...
THE TWO OF US WENT
TO EXPLORE A CAVE UP NORTH,
AND BY ACCIDENT,
SHE CROSSED THE BOUNDARY
INTO THE DARK TERRITORY,
A PLACE NO HUMAN
IS ALLOWED TO ENTER, EVER.
THE TABOO INDEX FORBIDS IT.
Kirito: TABOO INDEX?
Eugeo: THE NEXT DAY,
AN INTEGRITY KNIGHT
CAME TO OUR VILLAGE...
AND HE TOOK HER TO CENTORIA
TO BE EXECUTED.
BUT I STILL BELIEVE
SHE’S ALIVE, KIRITO.
I KNOW IT.
SOMEWHERE IN CENTORIA,
ALICE IS ALIVE.
Kirito: ALICE.
I KNOW THAT NAME.
ALICE.
- Eugeo: I’M SORRY.
- ( Kirito gasps )
Eugeo: I DIDN’T MEAN
TO DUMP ALL THAT ON YOU.
I KNOW WE JUST MET AND ALL,
BUT IT FEELS
LIKE WE’RE OLD FRIENDS.
Kirito: OH, THAT’S OKAY.
I DON’T MIND.
SO WHY DON’T YOU GO FIND HER?
GO TO CENTORIA OR WHEREVER,
SEE IF SHE’S THERE?
Eugeo: EVEN IF I HAD
THE FASTEST HORSE IN THE LAND,
IT WOULD TAKE A WEEK
TO GET THERE FROM HERE.
Kirito: THEN THROW SOME CLOTHES
AND FOOD IN A BAG AND WALK.
Eugeo: IF I COULD
DO THAT, I WOULD,
BUT I CAN’T
JUST ABANDON MY CALLING.
THE TABOO INDEX FORBIDS IT.
YOU KNOW THAT.
Kirito: OH, RIGHT.
YOU GOT A POINT.
UM...
SORRY TO BE NOSY,
BUT ABOUT HOW LONG AGO
DID ALL THIS HAPPEN, ANYWAY?
Eugeo: IT WAS MY 11th SUMMER,
SIX YEARS AGO.
WANT SOME WATER?
( Kirito gasps )
THANKS. MAYBE LATER.
( Eugeo chuckles )
WELL, LUNCH IS OVER,
SO I BETTER GET BACK TO WORK.
I STILL HAVE TO MEET
MY QUOTA FOR TODAY.
Kirito: I’LL JUST KICK BACK
’TIL YOU FINISH, THEN.
BY THE WAY, YOUR CALLING,
WHAT IS IT?
Eugeo: YOU’LL SEE.
IT’S NOT VERY EXCITING.
( ax chops )
( ax rings )
( Eugeo sighs )
( sighs )
Kirito: SO, LIKE, YOUR CALLING’S
TO CHOP DOWN TREES?
Eugeo: YEAH.
OFFICIALLY, MY TITLE’S
SUPPOSED TO BE WOODCUTTER.
THE PROBLEM IS, I HAVEN’T
CUT A SINGLE TREE DOWN
IN THE SEVEN YEARS
SINCE I RECEIVED MY CALLING.
Kirito: WHAT?
Eugeo: MY JOB’S
TO WORK ON THIS TREE.
IT’S CALLED THE GIGAS CEDAR.
THE VILLAGERS CALL IT
SOMETHING ELSE, THOUGH...
"THE DEMON TREE."
THEY CALL IT THAT,
BECAUSE IT SUCKS UP
ALL OF TERRARIA’S BLESSINGS
FROM THE LAND AROUND IT.
RULID HAS ALWAYS WANTED
TO PLANT MORE WHEAT FIELDS,
BUT AS LONG AS THIS IS HERE,
NOTHING GOOD WILL GROW.
THE VILLAGE
HAD THAT DRAGONBONE AX
SENT FROM THE CAPITAL
AND APPOINTED A WOODCUTTER
TO WORK ON IT EVERY DAY
’TIL THE TREE CAME DOWN.
THAT’S MY JOB.
Kirito: SO FOR
THE PAST SEVEN YEARS NOW,
YOU’VE BEEN
CHOPPING AWAY AT IT?
AFTER ALL THAT TIME,
THAT’S AS FAR AS YOU GOT?
- ( Eugeo chuckles ) HARDLY.
- Kirito: EH?
Eugeo: I’M ACTUALLY
A SEVENTH-GENERATION WOODCUTTER.
THAT’S OUR CALLING.
SOMEONE’S BEEN
CHOPPING AWAY ON IT
EVERY SINGLE DAY
FOR 300 YEARS, IN FACT.
Kirito: F-FOR 300 YEARS?!
HEY, EUGEO...
MIND IF I TAKE A CRACK AT IT?
Eugeo: HUH?!
Kirito: I MEAN, YOU DID GIVE ME
HALF YOUR LUNCH, DIDN’T YOU?
SO IT’S ONLY FAIR I SHOULD
PICK UP HALF YOUR WORK.
Eugeo: OH, I DON’T KNOW. I MEAN,
THE TABOO INDEX DOESN’T SAY
I CAN’T HAVE SOMEONE HELP,
EVEN THOUGH IT IS
MY CALLING AND ALL.
TRY IT, BUT IT’S
MUCH HARDER THAN IT LOOKS.
Kirito: I WON’T KNOW ’TIL I TRY.
HERE GOES NOTHIN’.
♪
( yells )
( groans )
- ( wincing )
- ( Eugeo laughing )
Kirito: YOU DON’T
HAVE TO LAUGH THAT HARD.
Eugeo: I’M SORRY ABOUT THAT.
YOU PUT WAY TOO MUCH TENSION
INTO YOUR SHOULDERS AND HIPS.
RELAX, AND LET THE MOMENTUM
DO THE WORK FOR YOU.
Kirito: THAT’S RIGHT.
THIS IS A VIRTUAL WORLD.
IT’S NOT ABOUT MY REAL ABILITY,
BUT MY AVATAR’S.
♪
( breathes deeply )
SWORD SKILL, SMASH!
( yells )
( sighs )
Eugeo: WHOA,
THAT WAS A NICE HIT!
GO ON. GIVE IT ANOTHER SHOT,
BEFORE YOU FORGET.
Kirito: 50!
( ax chops )
( sighs )
Eugeo: OKAY,
THAT’S 1,000 STRIKES.
Kirito: REALLY?
WE DID THAT MANY TODAY?
Eugeo: UH-HUH. 500 FOR ME,
AND 500 FOR YOU.
ADD THE 1,000
I DID THIS MORNING,
AND THAT’S 2,000 STRIKES TOTAL.
THAT’S THE DAILY QUOTA
FOR MY CALLING.
( Kirito laughs )
( thinking ) OH, MY GOD.
Eugeo: YOU’RE A NATURAL
AT THIS, KIRITO.
THANKS TO YOUR SKILL,
I HAD AN EASY DAY TODAY.
Kirito: I DON’T KNOW ABOUT THAT.
I BET YOU WOULD HAVE
HAD IT CUT IT DOWN BY NOW
IF I WASN’T HERE
MESSING AROUND.
Eugeo: UH...
THINK SO?
THEN YOU NEED TO SEE SOMETHING.
( Kirito gasps )
Eugeo: IT’S ONLY GONE DOWN
BY ABOUT 50 SINCE LAST MONTH.
THAT’S NORMAL, ACTUALLY.
IT’S A STRONG TREE.
SO WHAT IF WE DIDN’T MAKE
A LOT OF PROGRESS TODAY?
IN THE END,
IT DOESN’T REALLY MAKE
MUCH OF A DIFFERENCE AT ALL.
( chuckles )
LET’S GO.
Kirito: WAIT.
YOU FORGOT TO LOCK IT.
Eugeo: WHAT FOR?
Kirito: WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
SOMEONE COULD STEAL IT.
Eugeo: NOW, WHO’D DO THAT?
IT CLEARLY STATES
IN THE TABOO INDEX
THAT THEFT
IS FORBIDDEN, REMEMBER?
Kirito: OH. YEAH, THAT’S RIGHT.
Eugeo: COME ON.
I’LL SHOW YOU MY VILLAGE.
Kirito: UM, BUT--
HEY, WAIT UP!
♪
HUH?
Guard: HEY, EUGEO.
WHO’S YOUR NEW FRIEND?
Eugeo: HEY, ZINK.
THIS IS KIRITO.
I THINK HE’S
A LOST CHILD OF VECTA.
Zink: THAT TRUE?
YOU CAN’T REMEMBER ANYTHING?
Kirito: UM, NO?
Zink: DID YOU FORGET
YOUR CALLING, TOO?
Kirito: YEAH, I GUESS.
Zink: HMPH.
IT WAS PROBABLY
A LOUSY CALLING, ANYWAY.
BET IT WAS
AS LAME AS EUGEO’S HERE.
HE’S GOT ONE
OF THE MOST POINTLESS CALLINGS
IN ALL THE LAND!
NOW, MINE, I’M A MAN-AT ARMS,
- AND LET ME TELL--
- Kirito: SWORDSMAN.
THAT’S MY CALLING, MAN.
I’M A SWORDSMAN.
Zink: A SWORDSMAN?
A SCRAWNY, WEAK-LOOKIN’
PIPSQUEAK LIKE YOU?
YOU CAN’T EVEN LIFT A SWORD.
HMPH.
GO ON, THEN.
SHOW US YOUR "SKILL."
( Kirito chuckles )
LET’S SEE HOW I DO WITH THIS.
♪
( Eugeo stammering )
( Kirito yells )
( both gasp )
Kirito: NO WAY.
THAT WAS A LIGHT EFFECT.
THERE’S SWORD SKILLS HERE.
Eugeo: THAT WAS AMAZING!
I DIDN’T KNOW
YOU HAD SKILLS LIKE THAT!
MAYBE YOU WERE A SENTINEL
IN SOME BIG CITY.
Kirito: I-I DON’T KNOW, MAYBE.
- Eugeo: ZINK?
- ( Zink gasps )
Eugeo: WILL YOU LET KIRITO IN?
I’D LIKE TO SHOW HIM
AROUND THE VILLAGE NOW.
♪
Kirito: I’M TIRED.
Eugeo: WELL, WE’RE HERE.
Kirito: FINALLY.
IS THIS REALLY OKAY? I MEAN,
EVERYONE’S JUST GONNA ACCEPT I’M
ONE OF THOSE LOST VECTA KIDS?
Eugeo: ISN’T THAT WHAT YOU ARE?
Kirito: YEAH. I GUESS SO.
Eugeo: LET’S TALK TO THE SISTER
AND GET YOU SORTED OUT.
( door opens )
Azalia: WHAT DO YOU BOYS WANT?
Kirito: UH, I...
Sister: HMM?
( gasps )
( Eugeo gasps )
( sighs )
Sister: HERE. I BROUGHT YOU
A PILLOW AND A BLANKET.
PRAYERS BEGIN AT 6:00.
BREAKFAST IS AT 7:00.
I’LL COME CHECK ON YOU,
BUT PLEASE TRY
TO GET UP ON TIME.
DO NOT BE LATE FOR PRAYERS.
YOU DO NOT WANT
TO MAKE SISTER AZALIA MAD.
ALSO, WE HAVE A CURFEW
AFTER LIGHTS-OUT, SO MIND THAT.
( girl gasps ) SHE SAW US!
- Boy: RUN!
- ( sister sighs )
HONESTLY.
NOW THEN, DO YOU
HAVE ANY QUESTIONS?
Kirito: NO, I’M GOOD.
THANKS FOR SETTING ME UP.
( sister sighs )
WELL, GOOD NIGHT, THEN.
YOU KNOW HOW TO PUT OUT
THE LAMP, RIGHT?
Kirito: YEAH.
GOOD NIGHT, SELKA.
( Selka grunts )
( Kirito sighs )
THIS AIN’T THE REAL WORLD,
AND AS FAR AS I CAN TELL,
NONE OF THE VILLAGERS ARE NPCs.
BUT THEY CAN’T
BE TESTERS, EITHER.
THERE’D HAVE TO BE
DOZENS OF S.T.L.s
FOR THEM TO LOG IN WITH,
AND I KNOW
THERE AREN’T THAT MANY.
WHAT’D EUGEO SAY?
( no audible dialogue )
ACCORDING TO HIM,
MORE THAN 300 YEARS
HAVE PASSED IN THIS WORLD.
HE’S SPENT THE LAST SIX
AS A WOODCUTTER HERE
AND REMEMBERS
HIS CHILDHOOD HERE, TOO.
IF THAT’S TRUE,
THEN HIM AND THE OTHERS...
HMM? ( gasps )
OH.
EUGEO AND THE VILLAGERS
WERE RAISED HERE FROM THE START,
BUT THE ONLY WAY
THAT COULD HAPPEN
IS IF RATH COPIED
THE SOULS OF BABIES.
BABIES...
ARTIFICIAL FLUCTLIGHTS.
IT’S HARD TO BELIEVE, BUT
THERE’S NO OTHER EXPLANATION.
BUT WHY WOULD RATH DO THAT?
AND HOW FAST WOULD THEY
HAVE TO ACCELERATE TIME
TO GET THIS WORLD TO THIS POINT?
AND WHAT IF I’M
STUCK HERE FOREVER
AND NEVER GET BACK HOME?
MAYBE I CAN
GET IN TOUCH WITH KIKUOKA
IF I GET TO A BIGGER CITY.
I NEED MONEY TO TRAVEL,
AND, RIGHT NOW, I GOT NONE,
AND I DON’T KNOW ENOUGH
ABOUT THIS WORLD YET.
IF I HAD SOME HELP,
I COULD GET TO CENTORIA
AND FIND SOME ANSWERS THERE.
♪
( woman vocalizing )
♪ THE IRIS TO YOU ♪
NEXT TIME: THE END MOUNTAINS